

ABOUT ME

- 06/12/1996
- French
- Driving License

CONTACT

P: +33 6 08 12 03 73
E: quentin.roudier@outlook.fr
A: 58 rue François Pinson, 92320,
Chatillon, France
L: quentin-roudier-546008150

IT SKILLS

- Python (Flask, Numpy, Panda, Tensorflow, ROS)
- Javascript (Node.js, React.js, jQuery, Express.js)
- HTML, CSS
- Git, GitHub
- SQL, MongoDB
- RESTful API

SOFTWARES

- Solidworks, CATIA, FUSION 360
- Arduino
- Matlab & Simulink
- Pack Office

ENGINEERING

- Robotics
- Mechatronics
- Image Processing

LANGUAGES

French: Mother tongue English: Advanced

Japanese: Pre-Intermediate

German: Elementary

HOBBIES

Entomology (holder of a 200specimens collection), drawing, coding, reading, travel, self-defense

QUENTIN ROUDIER

ABOUT

Passionated about new technologies, I always want to get out of my comfort zone to improve my skills and understand the world around me. After working in a field as large as mechatronics is, I understood that coding is the part that I prefer and where I would be the most flourished. This is the reason why I'm looking now for an IT job such as software engineer or web developper. As a fast learner and a curious person, I know I can adapt quicly to new environnments like I did in my previous experiences.

WORK EXPERIENCE

- CONSULTING ENGINEER IN PYTHON, MECHATRONICS AND TEST DEVELOPMENT SII working for MBDA and THALES and the internal Data Sciences Laboratory of SII \mid August 2020 Today
 - Python, C and Atlas scripts development
 - Code review and maintenance
 - Analysis of the hardware part of the system for debugging
- MECHATRONICS / ROBOTICS ENGINEER

DEMBoost | Oct 2019 - Feb 2020

- Innovating robotic solutions for nuclear decommissioning
- Designing the functional and behavioral system architectures of the robots
- Learning how to use ROS and simulating robotic tasks
- Simulating systems and creating algorithms on Matlab/Simulink and in Python
- Creating a robotic prototype system for radiological cartography in radioactive environments
- Learning about robotics in hostile environments
- MECHATRONICS / ROBOTICS INTERN

DEMBoost | Feb 2019 - Jul 2019

- Conceptions of robotic systems operating in hostile environments, mapping it and its radioactive emissions and taking samples of radioactive concrete.
- Presenting the robotics systems to the head of the French Atomic Energy Commission
- R&D INTERN IN POWER ELECTRONICS

Nagaoka University Of Technology in Japan | Mar 2018 - Jun 2018

- Studying the following subject: Single-phase power decoupling technique utilizing Hybrid method with passive and active power decoupling
- Simulate the electrical system on Simulink
- Participate to the redaction of a scientific paper

EDUCATION

WEB DEVELOPMENT FORMATION

'The Complete 2021 Web Development Bootcamp' sur Udemy | 2021 ENGINEERING DEGREE (M2), MAJOR IN INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING

ESIEE Amiens (Superior engineering school in electronics and electrotechnics) | 2014 - 2019 RESEARCH MASTER (M2), MAJOR IN COMPLEX SYSTEM ENGINEERING - MECHATRONICS SYSTEMS

UTC (University of Technology of Compiegne) - Sorbonne University | 2019 - 2019

PROJECTS

- CV WEBSITE WITH REACT AND NODE Personnal project, in progress
- TO DO LIST APP WITH MONGODB UDEMY
- "SIMON" GAME IN JAVASCRIPT UDEMY
- MODIFIED CHESS GAME IN PYTHON Personnal project